Mss.B.F327
American Philosophical Society
The Sol Feinstone Collection of the American Revolution, ca. 1760s-1850s
Circa 1760s-1850s
Mss.B.F327
American Philosophical Society
2.5 Linear feet Ca. 2500 items
Ca. 2500 items, 2.5 feet.
This rich collection of letters and documents, which was assembled by Sol Feinstone (1888-1980) over a period of fifty years, includes material on almost all notable Americans of that era, as well as prominent Europeans, and there are documents relating to military affairs. There are substantial groups of letters from: John Adams, Henry Dearborn, Alexander Hamilton, Jedediah Huntington, Thomas Jefferson, Lafayette, George Washington, and a long run of letters from a Massachusetts military surgeon named Samuel Adams. Many letters, though written by Revolutionary figures, relate to events that occurred before or after the War.
Feinstone, Sol,1888-1980,collector.
Box 1-5
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Deposited by the David Library, 1969.
Existence and Location of Copies note
This collection is also available on microfilm (Rhistoric Publications, 1969; 5 reels, Film 1274).
General note
A calendar is being prepared by David Fowler of the David Library. Only scanned items are noted below.
Naval History Note
The David Library Collection includes miscellaneous letters of high interest pertaining to all aspects of the American Revolution, including naval concerns. Among topics covered are privateers and privateering, prize cases, the British and Continental Navies, and the United States Navy and Marine Corps. There are also letters from John Barry, Francois-Joseph-Paul comte de Grasse, John Paul Jones, and Sir Richard Howe.
Early American History Note
The Sol Feinstone Collection of the David Library contains a wide array of original documents relating to the American Revolution. The collection is particularly strong in military affairs and contains a variety of original letters from generals and prominent officers from both British and American forces. The collection has a notable amount of papers relating to George Washington and his family, including a deed from 1604 to Laurence Washington that contains an original seal from James I.
In addition to the more well-known letter writers, the collection also houses significant letters, proclamations, and other records that offer insight into the social and political effects of the American Revolution. Of particular note are a series of letters from Samuel Adams Jr., son of Sam Adams and a medical officer in the Continental Army, which recount his experience. There is also a report on a woman in New Jersey who disguised herself as a man and enlisted in the militia, only to be discovered. There are also numerous letters from the early federal period which capture ratification debates and the history of the first congress.
Because Feinstone was from the Pennsylvania area, the Collection contains additional documents on Pennsylvania history, such as detailed sketches of wagons that operated in the 1770s and various land records.
The Collection has a detailed guide with an index.
Adams, John, 1735-1826; Adams, Samuel; Dearborn, Henry, 1751-1829; Hamilton, Alexander, 1757-1804; Huntington, Jedediah, 1743-1818; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826; Lafayette, Marie Joseph Paul Yves, marquis de, 1757-1834; Washington, George, 1732-1799; American Revolution; Business and Skilled Trades; Colonial Politics; Colony and State Specific History; Diplomatic History; Early National Politics; Family Correspondence; General Correspondence; Military History; Military Records; Miscellaneous; New Jersey -- History -- 1775-1865.; New Jersey -- History -- Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775.; Official Government Documents and Records; Pennsylvania History; Political Correspondence; Presidents.; Printed Material; Statesmen.; United States -- Armed Forces -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783.; United States -- History -- 1775-1865.; United States -- History -- Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775.; United States -- History, Military.
- New Jersey, 1776 November-1777 March; No. 1
  Scope and Contents note
  "An account of money in the hands of sundry persons taken to purchase cloathing" (sic); includes references to types of clothing gathered and to whom they were delivered, and a notation for "Hospital at Springfield."
- Rev. Samuel Auchmuty to John Montresor, 1775 April 15; No. 2
- John Adam to William Livingston, 1782 January 28; No. 3
- John Adams to Abigail Adams, 1782 December 4; No. 4
- John Adams to Thomas Boylston Adams, 1795 April 26; No. 5
- John Adams to Caroline Amelia DeWint, 1820 January 24; No. 6
- John Adams to Edme Jacques Genet, 1778 July 12; No. 7
- John Adams to Edme Jacques Genet, 1778 August 1; No. 8
- John Adams to Edme Jacques Genet, 1778 June 8; No. 9
- John Adams to Edme Jacques Genet, 1778 December 11; No. 10
- John Adams to Jean Luzac, 1781 December 13; No. 11
- John Adams to John Marshall, 1806 July 17; No. 12
- John Adams to George Alexander Otis, 1821 January 16; No. 13
- John Adams to Dr. Benjamin Rush, 1809 February 20; No. 14
- John Adams to Dr. Benjamin Rush, 1813 April 18; No. 15
- John Adams to Joseph Palmer, 1776 April 2; No. 16
- Peter Adams to Thomas Sim Lee, 1780 January 7; No. 17
- Samuel Adams, M.D. to Sally Preston Adams, 1776-1781; No. 18
  Microfilm target that describes the following thirty letters.
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston, 1776 March 10; No. 19
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston, 1776 March 26; No. 20
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1776 October 5; No. 21
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1776 October 8; No. 22
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1776 October 14; No. 23
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1776 October 18; No. 24
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1776 November 9; No. 25
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1776 November 16; No. 26
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1778 June 7; No. 27
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1778 July 19, 20; No. 28
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1778 August 5; No. 29
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1778 August 19; No. 30
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1778 October 2; No. 31
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1778 October 31; No. 32
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1779 May 6; No. 33
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1779 May 15; No. 34
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1779 May 30; No. 35
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1779 August 11; No. 36
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1779 November 20; No. 37
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1779 December 2; No. 38
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1779 December 9; No. 39
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1779 December 12; No. 40
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1780 January 1; No. 41
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1780 January 20; No. 42
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1780 March 21; No. 43
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1780 August 17; No. 44
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1780 December 2; No. 45
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1780 December 12; No. 46
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1780 December 20; No. 47
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Sally Preston Adams, 1781 October 3; No. 48
- Dr. Samuel Adams to Samuel Adams, 1775 February 7; No. 49
- Samuel Adams to James Lovell, 1778 March 31; No. 50
- John Adlam to William Adair, 1752 December 7; No. 51
- William Alexander, Lord Stirling to James Abeel, 1779 November 24; No. 52
- William Alexander, Lord Stirling to the Chairman of the New York Committee of Safety (Pierre Van Cortlandt), 1776 March 18; No. 53
- William Alexander, Lord Stirling to the Quartermaster General (Nathanael Greene), 1778 December 27; No. 54
- William Alexander, Lord Stirling to ________, 1765 February 23; No. 55
- Colony of East Florida, Court of Vice Admiralty, 1778 January 21; No. 56
- Frances Alsop to Evert Bancker, Jr., 1778 April 10, May 9, October 13; No. 57
- American Philosophical Society to David Reddick, 1789 January 17; No. 58
- Fisher Ames to John Lowell, 1789 July 28; No. 59
- John Anderson to "Josias" Tobias Lear, 1794 January 6; No. 60
- Peter Anspach to David Wolfe, 1793 January 17; No. 61
- John Armstrong to the Treasurer of the United States (Thomas Tudor Tucker), 1805 June 19; No. 62
- John Arndt to Joseph Reed, 1781 May 12; No. 63
- Benedict Arnold to "Peggy" Margaret Mansfield Arnold, 1768 September 25; No. 64
- Benedict Arnold to John Denny, 1780 September 4; No. 65
- Benedict Arnold to Dr. John Dickinson, 1765 March 2; No. 66
- Benedict Arnold to John Graves Simcoe, 1781 March 15; No. 67
- Benedict Arnold to Jacob Thompson, 1780 February 3; No. 68
- Regarding Samuel Ashton, 1804 March 30; No. 69
- William Austin to John Barry, 1786 April 7; No. 70
- Amos Avery, Andrew Huntington, and others, selectmen to Ephraim Herick, 1781 March 15; No. 71
- William Axtell to Samuel Blachley, 1779 April 16; No. 72
- Loammi Baldwin to Mary Baldwin, 1776 June 10; No. 73
- Nisbet Balfour to the American militia prisoners aboard the prison ship Torbay, 1781 May 17; No. 74
- John Banister to Theodorick Bland, 1777 November 12; No. 75
- William Barber to Henry Jackson, 1778 June; No. 76
- John Barr to Edward Dunscomb, 1782-1783; No. 77
- Henry Barry to All whom it may concern, 1779 February 5; No. 78
- State of Pennsylvania, Court of Admirality, 1776 September 9 - November 19; No. 79
- William Barton to his father (Gilbert Barton), 1779 June 4; No. 80
- William Barton to Benjamin Lawrence, 1779 August 15, 17; No. 81
- William Barton to ________, 1778 November 17; No. 82
- William Bayard. Port of New York., 1805 March 8; No. 83
- Rev. Joseph Bean, 1775 May 11; No. 84; 1.0 vol.
- John Beckley to Dr. William Eustis, 1804 July 17; No. 85
- John Beckley to ________, 1793 June 22, 25, 27, July 1, 2; No. 86
- George Beckwith to ________, 1779 October 17; No. 87
- Anthony Benezet to John Smith, n.d.; No. 88
- Asaph Bennet, 1778 July 24-30; No. 89
- John Beresford to ________, 1779 June 24; No. 90
- William M. Betts to the commanding officer at Fishkill, 1780 September 10; No. 91
- Clement Biddle to Jeremiah Wadsworth, 1779 November 9; No. 92
- Owen Biddle to Henry Hollingsworth, 1780 June 30; No. 93
- Ephraim Blaine to John Ladd Howell, 1779 January 8; No. 94
- Edward Blake, 1778 May 19; No. 95
- Massachusetts, Town of Boston, Committee of Correspondence to Samuel Robinson and others, 1773 January 7; No. 96
- Massachusetts, Town of Boston, Committee of Correspondence, Inspection and Safety to the Committee of Correspondence, Inspection, and Safety of the Town of Sandwich, Mass., 1777 February 27; No. 97
- Massachusetts, Port of Boston and Charleston to the Inspector of the Port, 1826 September 8; No. 98
- Massachusetts, Inhabitants of Town of Boston to the town clerk of Haverhill, Mass., 1774 July 26; No. 99
- Elias Boudinot, 1799 November 5; No. 100
- Elias Boudinot, Agent for James Drummond, Earl of Perth, and Rachael Drummond to Elijah Allen, 1799 May 1; No. 101
- Elias Boudinot to Elbridge Gerry, 1777 November 13; No. 102
- Elias Boudinot to William Irvine, 1801 May 23; No. 103
- Elias Boudinot to Robert Morris, 1781 February 7; No. 104
- Ephraim Bowen to Elisha Reynolds Potter, 1832 November 29; No. 105
- Jacob Bower, 1777-1779; No. 106; 1.0 vol.
- Matly Boyd to Benjamin Lawrence, 1776 April 22; No. 107
- Thomas Bradford to All concerned, 1780 July 14; No. 108
- William Bradford to the President Benjamin Franklin in Council of Pennsylvania, 1788 January 14; No. 109
- Isaac Bradish, 1783 May 3; No. 110
- Battle of Brandywine, 1777 September 11; No. 111
- Edward Pelham Brenton, 1810-1812; No. 112
- George Brodie, 1780 September 20; No. 113
- John L. Bronck, and six others, 1782 April 23-1792 September 17; No. 114
- Benjamin Brooks, 1799 July; No. 115
- Andrew Brown to Henry Jackson, 1777 July 30; No. 116
- Andrew Brown to Henry Jackson, 1777 August 27; No. 117
- Gawen Brown, Jr. to Henry Jackson, 1778 September 8; No. 118
- Gawen Brown, Jr. to Henry Jackson, 1778 September 18; No. 119
- Arthur Browne, 1766 February 24-April 24; No. 120
- Arthur Browne, 1766 October 25-December 24; No. 121
- Arthur Browne to Robert Leake, 1766 October 25; No. 122
- Arthur Browne to the Contractors for Victualling His Majesty's Forces in North America, 1766 August 5; No. 123
- James Bruce to George Turner, 1779 June 25; No. 124
- Peter Bryan Bruin to Henry Jackson, 1778 October 5; No. 125
- Peter Bryan Bruin to Henry Jackson, 1778 October 6; No. 126
- Peter Bryan Bruin to Henry Jackson, 1778 October 26; No. 127
- Peter Bryan Bruin to Henry Jackson, 1778 November 6; No. 128
- James Bruyn to Edward Dunscomb, 1783 July 10; No. 129
- Matthew Buchanan to the Pennsylvania Committee of Safety, 1776 March 12; No. 130
- Ebenezer Buck to David Kelley, 1778 August 24; No. 131
- Timothy Taylor, 1786 October 10; No. 132
- John Burgoyne to Horatio Gates, 1777 October 9; No. 133
- John Burgoyne to Lord George Germain, 1777 October 20; No. 134
- William Heath to John Burgoyne, 1778 March 28; No. 135
- Edmund Burke to John King, 1796 October 27; No. 136
- John Burke to Dr. John Morgan, 1783 August 12; No. 137
- Aaron Burr, 1796 August 3; No. 138
- Aaron Burr, on behalf of Alexander Henry, 1787 May; No. 139
- Aaron Burr to Thomas Jefferson, 1801 June 4; No. 140
- Aaron Burr to Gurdon W. Lathrop, 1815 March 30; No. 141
- Aaron Burr to Jeremiah Wadsworth, 1779 August 15; No. 142
- Aaron Burr to Joseph Wheaton, 1806 April 22; No. 143
- Aaron Burr to ________, March 27; No. 144
- Pierce Butler to John Ross, 1799 August 8; No. 145
- Thomas Butler to Isaac Craig, 1796 June 21; No. 146
- Thomas Butler to John Bradstreet, 1756 May 20; No. 147
- Colony of New York, 1775-1776; No. 148
- Francis Cabot, Jr. to Samuel White, 1780 February 23; No. 149
- Alexander Cain, 1781 September 27; No. 150
- James Thomson Callender to William Young, 1797 April 8; No. 151
- Charles-Alexandre Calonne to M. Ribart, 1764 May 1; No. 152
- Francisco Luis Hector, Baron de Carondelet to ________, 1794 July 6; No. 153
- Charles Carroll, of Carrollton to William Gibbons, 1823 January 22, 24; No. 154
- Charles Carroll, of Carrollton to Henry Hollingsworth, 1776 July 12; No. 155
- Charles Carroll, of Carrollton to the cashier of the Office of Discount and Deposit, 1826 May 23; No. 156
- Robert Carter to Thomas Hooper, 1722 July 3; No. 157
- Daniel Carthy to John Fisher, 1780 December 29; No. 158
- Daniel Carthy to John Fisher, 1781 June 22; No. 159
- Daniel Carthy to John Fisher, 1782 April 9; No. 160
- Daniel Carthy to John Fisher, 1782 May 14; No. 161
- Thomas Cartwright to Henry Jackson, 1778 October 5; No. 162
- Thomas Cartwright and James Jones to Henry Jackson, 1777 May 16; No. 163
- Richard Caswell to John Coart, 1778 December 6; No. 164
- ________ to Stephen Chambers, 1781 February 5; No. 165
- Gibraltar, n.d.; No. 166
- Pennsylvania, a number of inhabitants of Chester County to the Representatives of the Freeman of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania in General Assembly, n.d.; No. 167
- Richard Claiborne to ________, 1780 January 4; No. 168
- Rev. William Clark to Samuel Holten, 1777 August 4; No. 169
- Matthew Clarkson to John Barry, 1779 February 13; No. 170
- Peter Clayes to Joseph "Balcom" Balcolm, 1783 January 24; No. 171
- Jacob Clingman to John Beckley, 1793 June 27; No. 172
- Sir Henry Clinton to Lord George Germain, 1779 February 3; No. 173
- Sir Henry Clinton to Charles Jenkinson, 1780 August 24; No. 174
- Sir Henry Clinton to David Thomas, 1781 March 19; No. 175
- James Clinton and Enoch Poor to John Sullivan, 1779 November 30; No. 176
- George Clymer to Tench Coxe, 1794 November 2; No. 177
- George Clymer to Samuel Meredith, 1810 February 17; No. 178
- George Clymer to Samuel Meredith, 1812? January 11; No. 179
- George Clymer to Susannah Wright, 1779 September 7; No. 180
- Henry Clymer to George Clymer, 1802 August 6; No. 181
- David Cobb to Elias Dayton, 1781 July 20; No. 182
- Christopher Codwise to Frederick Weisenfels, 1783 April 30; No. 183
- William Coit to ________, 1775 June; No. 184
- Ebenezer Cole, 1780 February 20; No. 185
- Regarding Benjamin Franklin, n.d.; No. 186
- Pierre de La Colomb to John Jay, President of Congress, 1779 late July-early August; No. 187
- Pierre-Emile Colomb to ________, 1794; No. 188
- Peter Colt, 1778 January 20; No. 189
- Massachusetts, Committee of Safety to John Thomas, n.d.; No. 190
- State of Connecticut, General Assembly, 1780 October 12-13, 16-17; No. 191
- State of Connecticut, Hartford County Court to the sheriff or constables, 1786 September 16; No. 192
- State of Connecticut, Attorney Andrew Adams to the county court, 1777 September 26; No. 193
- State of Connecticut, Pay-Table Office to John Lawrence, treasurer, 1783 May 23; No. 194
- State of Connecticut, Pay-Table Office to John Lawrence, treasurer, 1784 February 6; No. 195
- State of Connecticut, Windham County Court to Benjamin Tracy, 1802 December 27; No. 196
- Zachariah Connelly, 1776 September 13; No. 197
- Henry Seymour Conway to John Irwin, 1765 December 17; No. 198
- Thomas Conway to Robert Morris, 1777 August 9; No. 199
- Abel Cooley to Solomon Miller, Jr., 1777 June 19; No. 200
- Lord Charles Cornwallis to ______ MacLeod, 1795 December 21; No. 201
- Lord Charles Cornwallis to George Washington, 1777 April 3; No. 202
- John Cox to Henry Hollingsworth, 1778 October 16; No. 203
- John Cox to Henry Hollingsworth, 1779 July 8; No. 204
- Tench Coxe to Tobias Lear, 1791 December 29; No. 205
- Tench Coxe to John Wilcocks, 1784 April 20; No. 206
- Tench Coxe, 1797 April 5; No. 207
- Jacob Crane, 1780 June 11; No. 208
- Louis de Berton des Balbes de Quiers duc de Crillon-Mahon to M. de Mongelas, 1783 March 17; No. 209
- Zacheus Crocker to Samuel Chamberlain, 1777 August 15; No. 210
- Armand-Charles-Augustin de la Croix duc de Castries to Michel Setaro, 1797 August 24; No. 211
- William Crosbie to Sir Henry Clinton, 1782 March 9; No. 212
- John Crossan, 1781 September 26; No. 213
- Richard Cumberland to ________, 1776; No. 214
- John Cushing to John Turner, 1778 February 26; No. 215
- Joseph Cushing to Theophilus Cotton, 1777 July 22; No. 216
- Nathaniel Cushing, 1780 August 24; No. 217
- _______ Blambart? to Adam Philippe, Comte de Custine, 1792 November 2; No. 218
- Pierre de Villeneuve, 1792 December 18; No. 219
- Eleanor Parke Custis to James McHenry, 1798 July 26; No. 220
- John Custis and Tully Wise, 1791 September 21; No. 221
- William Daingerfield to the contractor for Winchester Barracks, 1783 July 16; No. 222
- Campbell Dalrymple to Robert Monckton, 1762 April 20; No. 223
- David Daniells to Asa Daniells, Jr., n.d.; No. 224
- Jules Daverzac, 1818 July; No. 225
- William Davis to Henry Jackson, 1778 August 7; No. 226
- John Day to Thomas Mifflin, 1775 August 22; No. 227
- William Day to John Johnson, 1740 June 5; No. 228
- Silas Deane to Robert Morris, 1776 March 8; No. 229
- Henry Dearborn to Tench Coxe, 1804 January 27; No. 230
- Henry Dearborn to Tench Coxe, 1804 June 14; No. 231
- Henry Dearborn to Tench Coxe, 1805 January 8; No. 232
- Henry Dearborn to Tench Coxe, 1805 February 28; No. 233
- Henry Dearborn to Tench Coxe, 1805 June 20; No. 234
- Henry Dearborn to Tench Coxe, 1805 January 21; No. 235
- Henry Dearborn to Tench Coxe, 1805 January 30; No. 236
- Henry Dearborn to Tench Coxe, 1806 March 5; No. 237
- Henry Dearborn to Tench Coxe, 1806 March 6; No. 238
- Henry Dearborn to Tench Coxe, 1806 March 12; No. 239
- Henry Dearborn to Tench Coxe, 1806 November 6; No. 240
- Henry Dearborn to Tench Coxe, 1808 February 26; No. 241
- Henry Dearborn to Tench Coxe, 1808 March 31; No. 242
- Henry Dearborn to Tench Coxe, 1808 October 17; No. 243
- Henry Dearborn to Henry Alexander Scammell Dearborn, 1808 March 8; No. 244
- Henry Dearborn to Henry Alexander Scammell Dearborn, 1822 May 9; No. 245
- Henry Dearborn to William Linnard, 1803 November 25; No. 246
- Henry Dearborn to William Linnard, "1806" 1807? January 8; No. 247
- Henry Dearborn to William Linnard, 1806 November 12; No. 248
- Henry Dearborn to William Linnard, 1806 December 1; No. 249
- Henry Dearborn to William Linnard, 1806 December 10; No. 250
- Henry Dearborn to William Linnard, 1806 December 29; No. 251
- Henry Dearborn to William Linnard, 1807 March 16; No. 252
- Henry Dearborn to William Linnard, 1807 April 16; No. 253
- Henry Dearborn to William Linnard, 1807 May 28; No. 254
- Henry Dearborn to William Linnard, 1807 October 24; No. 255
- Henry Dearborn to William Linnard, 1807 December 14; No. 256
- Henry Dearborn to William Linnard, 1808 January 26; No. 257
- Henry Dearborn to William Linnard, 1808 February 22; No. 258
- Henry Dearborn to William Linnard, 1808 November 21; No. 259
- Henry Dearborn to William Linnard, 1808 December 6; No. 260
- Henry Dearborn to William Linnard, 1808 December 15; No. 261
- Julius Deming to Ebenezer Foote, 1778 November 27; No. 262
- Julius Deming to Ebenezer Foote, 1779 March 2; No. 263
- Julius Deming to Ebenezer Foote, 1779 September 11; No. 264
- Charles Dempsey, 1787 March 14; No. 265
- John Dennis to James "Robinson" [Robertson], 1779 January 4; No. 266
- George D'erbage to George Chalmers, 1779 April 9; No. 267
- N______ Thomas to Thomas Dering, 1752-1755; No. 268
- Moses Deshon, 1764 December 18; No. 269
- Richard Devens to "Eldrige" Elbridge Gerry, 1776 May 7; No. 270
- Massachusetts Clergyman, 1775; No. 271; 1.0 vol.
- Robert Digby to Paul Henry Curry, 1780 October 26; No. 272
- Robert Digby to Paul Henry Curry, 1780 October 25; No. 273
- Dr. Elijah Dix to whom it may concern, 1782 May 13; No. 274
- John A. Dix, 1862 April 20; No. 275
- Peter Dolliver to Henry Jackson, 1778 October 28; No. 276
- Alexander McDonald, 1779 December 24; No. 277
- John Robert Douglas to Major ______ Knolles, 1781 June 24; No. 278
- Amnason Dow to Josiah Bartlett, 1767 April 8; No. 279
- Richard Drakeford to Alexander Leslie, 1778 July 18; No. 280
- Friends Society of Philadelphia to the Senate and House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, 1793 December 6; No. 281
- Thomas Lundin, Lord Drummond to James Robertson, 1776 February 5; No. 282
- James Duane to John Tabor Kempe, 1774 October 11; No. 283
- James Duane to his children and to William North, 1790 July 26; No. 284
- William John Duane to Samuel B. Davis, 1837 March 31; No. 285
- Mathieu, Comte de Dumas to General Alexandre Berthier, 1801 November 17; No. 286
- Mathieu, Comte de Dumas to M. Lemaire, 1814 September 17; No. 287
- Mathieu, Comte de Dumas to M. Pelle, 1814 December 2; No. 288
- Charles-Francois Dumouriez to ________, 1762 September 17; No. 289
- Andrew Dunscomb to Edward Dunscomb, 1783 July 9; No. 290
- Edward Dunscomb to Peter Gansevoort, 1783 June 10; No. 291
- Edward Dunscomb to ________, 1783 June 3; No. 292
- Edward Dunscomb to ________, 1783 June 11; No. 293
- Edward Dunscomb to ________, 1783 August 2; No. 294
- Edward Dunscomb to Peter Gansevoort?, 1783; No. 295
- Peter Stephen Du Ponceau to Rev. Charles Rudolph Demme, 1834 July 19; No. 296
- Louis Le Begue de Presle Du Portail to M. ______ de Bayet, 1791 June 1; No. 297
- John Durkee to John Sumner, 1779 January 4; No. 298
- John Durkee to John Sumner, 1779 February 15; No. 299
- John Durkee to John Sumner, 1779 April 5; No. 300
- Massachusetts, Bristol County, Town of Easton to the constables of the town, 1776 March 2; No. 301
- Rev. Joseph Eckley to ________, n.d.; No. 302
- Rev. Joseph Eckley, 1787 April 22; No. 303
- Rev. Joseph Eckley, 1777 November; No. 304; 1.0 vol.
- Thomas Eddy, 1794 June 4; No. 305
- Hephzibah? Edwards to Mary Dering, October; No. 306
- Chevalier de L'Eguille, 1782 December 1; No. 307
- Dr. Jacob Ehrenzeller to Henry Jackson, 1778 October 1; No. 308
- Samuel Elbert to Lachlan McIntosh, 1777 April 24; No. 309
- Thomas Eliot to Matthew Bryant, 1769 August 23; No. 310